Hello, in this task we're
taking a look at the 'Either'
and 'Maybe' datatypes and their constructors,
by defining some values using said constructors.
We should already be familiar with the 'Maybe'
datatype from the lecture; the 'Maybe' datatype
represents an optional value, so a value of type
'maybe a' could be either something of type 'a',
represented with the 'Just a' constructor or it
could be empty, so no value at all, represented
with the 'Nothing' constructor. Whereas the
'Either' datatype represents a value with two
possibilities, a value of type 'a b' could be
either the value of type 'a', represented with
the 'Left a' constructor or something of type
'b', represented by the 'Right b' constructor.
At this point, we should note that these type
variables 'a' and 'b' don't necessarily have to
be different types. So we could go and say 'Either
String String' and then construct 'Left String'
and 'Right String' instances, for example, and
this would be valid. With that out of the way, we
can actually start solving the task, which is just
to take a look at these type signatures for these
values down here, and we should define valid
values fitting these type signatures for all
of these, with the added caveat that they need
to be discrete, so they need to be different
for each of these and we should use every data
constructor of 'Maybe' and 'Either' at least
once somewhere down in here. Starting with the
first value, we have the type signature of
'Either Bool' for our 'a', so if we look at
this as 'Either a b', our 'a' would be 'Bool'
and our 'b' would be a list with tuples
and 'Integer' and 'Bool' inside the tuple.
So here we can use the constructors 'Left' and
'Right', so if we just go 'Left' here we need to
use something of type 'Bool' for 'a', so go
with 'True' or 'False', which are the only
values for 'Bool', of course. And for value2, since
these are the same type signatures, we're gonna go
with the 'Right' constructor and build something
with the lists with tuple 'Integer', 'Bool'
type over here, so, of course, an
empty list would be acceptable,
or we can create a list with actual tuples
inside. Let's say tuple 10 and True for example,
and, of course, this could be a list
with multiple tuples, so 8 and False,
and these two would be valid values for values
one and two. Now these were pretty simple and
moving on from here we need to start
looking out for these parentheses here,
because sometimes they're going to signify that
it's a tuple and sometimes not; as you can
see in this case this is just parentheses around
these... this type thing, which over here is
defining this 'Either' over here; there's not
a comma over here, so this is not a tuple,
but there's a tuple inside of it, so we need to
take care to not get our tuple parentheses and
just regular parentheses confused here. So we
start with this; we have an outside tuple over
here consisting of 'Maybe' and this 'Either'
structure over here, and 'Maybe Integer',
so if we just go with the lazy round starting out
here, 'Maybe' has the constructors 'Nothing' and
'Just a', so we can go 'Nothing' and 'Nothing'
for example, because we have a tuple consisting
of two 'Maybe', so this is a valid value, or
of course you can use the 'Just' constructor
and for example say for the first 'Maybe' in our
tuple we're going to go with 'Just' and then we
need to look at this 'Either' construction over
here, which is 'Either' tuple 'Maybe Integer'
or 'Bool', and we can say for example: 'Left' and
then creating this tuple here 10 and 'Nothing'
for our 'Maybe' inside the tuple, or of course
'Just 2' for example, just some integer value,
and for our second part of the tuple for the
second 'Maybe Integer' over here you can go with
either 'Nothing', of course, or just any
integer, let's say 'Just 12' in this case.
For value five we have once again the same type
signature, so let's start again with 'Just'
and we use 'Left' over here, so we use 'Right'
now and 'Right' was of type 'Bool', so we're
gonna go 'Right True' here and for the other
side we're gonna go with 'Just', let's say 24,
because we could also go with 'Nothing' again over
here, but well you can decide that for yourself
which you want to use here. They just need to be
different for our task. Moving on with values six
and seven, these are just one 'Either' of either
'Maybe Integer' or 'Bool', this is a tuple again
here, so careful about looking at this. And
this is not a tuple, this is just a 'Maybe'
which could be a tuple of 'Integer', 'Maybe
Bool', or 'Nothing', of course, so since we have
two of these again, let's go with the 'Left'
and 'Right' constructors; let's go 'Left'
and create a tuple of 'Maybe Integer Bool' so just
1 for example, and 'True', or 'Nothing' of course.
And for our value seven we're gonna go with the
'Right' constructor and build this 'Maybe' value,
but we can just go with 'Right Nothing'
or 'Right Just' and then build the tuple
with 10 and 'Nothing' for 'Maybe Bool'
or 'Just 2' or 'Just 4' of course.
And now if we save all of this and reload
the task in ghci and just run the test,
we can see that indeed all of these tests are
checking if the conditions for the task are
met... try it out and we don't have any failures
so this is a correct solution for this task.